<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Oliver C. Stringham</title>
    <link>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/categories/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Oliver C. Stringham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/categories/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dataset of seized wildlife and their intended uses</title>
      <link>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/illegal-wildlife-trade-seizures-dataset/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/illegal-wildlife-trade-seizures-dataset/</guid>
      <description>Abstract     The illegal wildlife trade (IWT) threatens conservation and biosecurity efforts. The Internet has greatly facilitated the trade of wildlife, and researchers have increasingly examined the Internet to uncover illegal trade. However, most efforts to locate illegal trade on the Internet are targeted to one or few taxa or products. Large-scale efforts to find illegal wildlife on the Internet (e-commerce, social media, dark web) may be facilitated by a systematic compilation of illegally traded wildlife taxa and their uses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reptile smuggling is predicted by trends in the legal exotic pet trade</title>
      <link>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/australian-reptile-smuggling-predicted-by-legal-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/australian-reptile-smuggling-predicted-by-legal-trade/</guid>
      <description>Abstract     Live animal smuggling presents a suite of conservation and biosecurity concerns, including invasive species and disease risks. However, understanding why certain species are smuggled over others, and predicting which species will be smuggled, remains unexplored. Here, we compared the live reptile species smuggled to Australia (75 species) to the legal trade of live reptile species in the United States (US). Almost all smuggled species were found in the legal US exotic pet market (98.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text classification to streamline online wildlife trade analyses</title>
      <link>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/text-classification-to-streamline-online-wildlife-trade-analyses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/text-classification-to-streamline-online-wildlife-trade-analyses/</guid>
      <description>Abstract     Automated monitoring of websites that trade wildlife is increasingly necessary to inform conservation and biosecurity efforts. However, e-commerce and wildlife trading websites can contain a vast number of advertisements, an unknown proportion of which may be irrelevant to researchers and practitioners. Given that many wildlife-trade advertisements have an unstructured text format, automated identification of relevant listings has not traditionally been possible, nor attempted. Other scientific disciplines have solved similar problems using machine learning and natural language processing models, such as text classifiers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening protection of endemic wildlife threatened by the international pet trade: The case of the Australian shingleback lizard</title>
      <link>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/australian-shingleback-illegal-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/australian-shingleback-illegal-trade/</guid>
      <description>Abstract     Unsustainable wildlife trade threatens an increasing number of species globally. Australia has a particularly rich and endemic herpetofauna, which is coveted on the international pet market. While Australia implements domestic protection of most of its native species, there is little to no regulation of international trade once live animals have been smuggled out of the country. This is a threat for a variety of rare, unique and/or range-restricted species, subspecies and locality morphs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The International Vertebrate Pet Trade Network and Insights from US Imports of Exotic Pets</title>
      <link>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/pet-trade-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/pet-trade-network/</guid>
      <description>The international trade in exotic vertebrate pets provides key social and economic benefits but also drives associated ecological, ethical, and human health impacts. Here, we represent and review the structure of the pet trade as a network composed of different market actors (nodes) and trade flows (links). As a case study of how data-informed networks can realize this goal, we quantified spatial and temporal patterns in pets imported to the United States. Our framework and case study illustrate how network approaches can help to inform and manage the effects of the growing demand for exotic pets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing propagule pressure to prevent invasive species establishments: propagule size, number, and risk–release curve</title>
      <link>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/manage-propagule-pressure-to-prevent-invasive-species-establishments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/manage-propagule-pressure-to-prevent-invasive-species-establishments/</guid>
      <description>Keeping propagule pressure low can reduce the probability a non-native species will establish in a new location. Here we develop a mathematical framework that can determine the required reduction in levels for propagule size and number (representative of management actions) to maintain a target establishment probability. Our tool can serve to guide the development of new invasive species management plans in a transparent and quantitative manner. Together with information on the costs associated with approaches to reducing propagule pressure, our tool can be used to identify the most cost‐effective approach to prevent invasive species establishments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A guide to using the Internet to monitor and quantify the wildlife trade</title>
      <link>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/guide-to-using-internet-to-study-wildlife-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/guide-to-using-internet-to-study-wildlife-trade/</guid>
      <description>The internet is a vast source of wildlife trade data. Here, we present an accessible guide for Internet‐based wildlife trade surveillance, which uses a repeatable and systematic method to automate data collection from relevant websites. Our guide is adaptable to the multitude of trade‐based contexts including different focal taxa or derived parts, and locations of interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Australia’s wish list of exotic pets: biosecurity and conservation implications of desired alien and illegal pet species</title>
      <link>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/australia-desire-for-exotic-pets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/australia-desire-for-exotic-pets/</guid>
      <description>The live pet trade is a major pathways for invasive species. Australia imposes tough regulations against the trade of non-native animals as pets. However, there exists an illegal trade of these animals in Australia that threatens biosecurity. Here, we used government records of enquiries from the general public to assess the characteristics of species that are likely desired as pets. We found that desired species are more likely to invasive species elsewhere or at risk of extinction due to trade. Our findings suggest that in absence of strict laws, an unregulated pet trade would threaten Australian biosecurity and global conservation efforts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When pets become pests: the role of the exotic pet trade in producing invasive vertebrate animals</title>
      <link>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/when-pets-become-pests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/when-pets-become-pests/</guid>
      <description>The exotic pet trade is a multi-billion dollar industry involving thousands of animal species. Research has historically focused only the conservation and disease risks, however the risk of pets becoming invasive species has been overlooked. We show this trade is now the leading contributor of non-native establishments and invasions worldwide among vertebrates. We highlight areas of future research/policy changes needed to avoid more invasive pets in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pet problems: Biological and economic factors that influence the release of alien reptiles and amphibians by pet owners</title>
      <link>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/pet-problems-reptiles-amphibians-correlates-of-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/pet-problems-reptiles-amphibians-correlates-of-release/</guid>
      <description>The trade of non-native animals as pets the main pathway for new invasive species if they become released into the wild. Here, we examined the trade in non-native reptiles and amphibians as pets in the United States. We found c. 1,700 species traded in the past two decades of which 126 species have been recorded as released in the wild. Using machine learning models, we show that larger-bodied, longer-lived species, who sold for cheaper prices were more likely to have been released. We propose policies and education focused on species with these characteristics in order to curb the impacts of new invasive species that originated as pets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High annual survival in infected wildlife populations may veil a persistent extinction risk from disease</title>
      <link>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/indiana-bat-conservation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/indiana-bat-conservation/</guid>
      <description>White-nose syndrome (WNS) has caused catastrophic declines in some bat species, while others appear less impacted. We conducted a mark–recapture study of federally endangered Indiana bats (Myotis sodalis) during 2011–2016 and found survival had decreased by around 4 percentage points. We ran population models based on new survival data and results suggested there will be future population declines for the Indiana bat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Tool for Making Policy Recommendations Based on PVA: Helping Theory Become Practice</title>
      <link>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/conservation-policy-recommendations-from-pva/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/conservation-policy-recommendations-from-pva/</guid>
      <description>Mathematical models that inform conservation efforts always have underlying uncertainty. We show that in many applied cases, this uncertainty results in a non-trivial probability that management action will have no benefit to conservation. We encourage future use of population viability analysis (PVA) to explicitly account for this uncertainty when considering whether or not to implement management actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A modeling methodology to evaluate the efficacy of predator exclosures versus predator control</title>
      <link>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/modelling-predator-exclosures-vs-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/modelling-predator-exclosures-vs-control/</guid>
      <description>Endangered species face many threats, including from invasive predators. Here, we developed a modelling method to compare different management options for controlling predators. We then applied this method to compared management options for the endangered shorebird, the piping plover, which faces predation threats from the red fox along New Jersey beaches.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
