<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>illegal wildlife trade on Oliver C. Stringham</title>
    <link>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/tags/illegal-wildlife-trade/</link>
    <description>Recent content in illegal wildlife trade on Oliver C. Stringham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/tags/illegal-wildlife-trade/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dataset of seized wildlife and their intended uses</title>
      <link>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/illegal-wildlife-trade-seizures-dataset/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/illegal-wildlife-trade-seizures-dataset/</guid>
      <description>Abstract     The illegal wildlife trade (IWT) threatens conservation and biosecurity efforts. The Internet has greatly facilitated the trade of wildlife, and researchers have increasingly examined the Internet to uncover illegal trade. However, most efforts to locate illegal trade on the Internet are targeted to one or few taxa or products. Large-scale efforts to find illegal wildlife on the Internet (e-commerce, social media, dark web) may be facilitated by a systematic compilation of illegally traded wildlife taxa and their uses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reptile smuggling is predicted by trends in the legal exotic pet trade</title>
      <link>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/australian-reptile-smuggling-predicted-by-legal-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/australian-reptile-smuggling-predicted-by-legal-trade/</guid>
      <description>Abstract     Live animal smuggling presents a suite of conservation and biosecurity concerns, including invasive species and disease risks. However, understanding why certain species are smuggled over others, and predicting which species will be smuggled, remains unexplored. Here, we compared the live reptile species smuggled to Australia (75 species) to the legal trade of live reptile species in the United States (US). Almost all smuggled species were found in the legal US exotic pet market (98.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text classification to streamline online wildlife trade analyses</title>
      <link>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/text-classification-to-streamline-online-wildlife-trade-analyses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/text-classification-to-streamline-online-wildlife-trade-analyses/</guid>
      <description>Abstract     Automated monitoring of websites that trade wildlife is increasingly necessary to inform conservation and biosecurity efforts. However, e-commerce and wildlife trading websites can contain a vast number of advertisements, an unknown proportion of which may be irrelevant to researchers and practitioners. Given that many wildlife-trade advertisements have an unstructured text format, automated identification of relevant listings has not traditionally been possible, nor attempted. Other scientific disciplines have solved similar problems using machine learning and natural language processing models, such as text classifiers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening protection of endemic wildlife threatened by the international pet trade: The case of the Australian shingleback lizard</title>
      <link>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/australian-shingleback-illegal-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/australian-shingleback-illegal-trade/</guid>
      <description>Abstract     Unsustainable wildlife trade threatens an increasing number of species globally. Australia has a particularly rich and endemic herpetofauna, which is coveted on the international pet market. While Australia implements domestic protection of most of its native species, there is little to no regulation of international trade once live animals have been smuggled out of the country. This is a threat for a variety of rare, unique and/or range-restricted species, subspecies and locality morphs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Response to the Department of Agriculture, Water and the Environment&#39;s &#39;Import risk review for psittacine birds from all countries&#39;</title>
      <link>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/response-to-dawe-parrot-risk-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/response-to-dawe-parrot-risk-review/</guid>
      <description>We provide comments to The Department of Agriculture, Water and the Environment on their ‘Import risk review for psittacine birds from all countries’ draft report. Due to  serious key omissions, we do not support the import of psittacine birds based on the evidence provided in the risk review. The report does not provide sufficient transparency, nor evidence-based assessments of all benefits, risks, or associated costs, of allowing the import of psittacine birds. If the Department wishes to pursue this assessment, then future risk reviews must include the associated costs of facilitating new invasive species, and provide justification on the broader societal benefits of allowing import of psittacine birds. It is our professional scientific opinion that the benefits of importing psittacine birds are outweighed by the significant damages caused by the potential introduction of new invasive species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Illegal Wildlife Trade: A Threat to Environmental Biosecurity, Biodiversity, Human Health and Wellbeing</title>
      <link>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/illegal-wildlife-trade-infographic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliverstringham.netlify.app/publications/illegal-wildlife-trade-infographic/</guid>
      <description>Illegal wildlife trade (IWT) directly threatens tens of thousands of species. It is critical that it is taken seriously in order to safeguard our environmental assets and provide resilient landscapes for our unique flora and fauna. Here, we provide an infographic of IWT including: what it is, how bad is it, why can&amp;rsquo;t we stop it, and solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
